Have you ever thought about what's not happening?
何が起こっていないか考えたことはありますか？
Kind of sounds like a riddle, right?
ちょっとした謎かけみたいですね。
Well, today we're gonna be grammar detectives.
今日は文法探偵になりましょう。
And our mission is to figure out how to talk about all the things
私たちのミッションは、今起こっていないことを話す方法を見つけることです。
that aren't happening right now. Let's get into it.
さあ、始めましょう。
Okay, so picture this.
では、これを想像してみてください。
You text your friend who lives in America and nothing.
アメリカに住む友達にメッセージを送ったけど、返事がない。
You're waiting and waiting. Are they ignoring you? Nah, probably not.
待っているけど、無視されているのかな？ いや、たぶん違う。
But it makes you wonder, what are they not doing?
でも、彼らは何をしていないのか気になります。
Well, for starters, they're not looking at their phone.
まず、彼らは携帯電話を見ていない。
We're gonna figure out exactly how to say that and a whole lot more.
それをどう言うか、そしてもっとたくさんのことを考えましょう。
So before we dive into the new stuff, let's do a super quick warm-up.
新しいことに入る前に、簡単なウォームアップをしましょう。
We're just gonna review something you probably already know,
あなたがすでに知っていることを復習します。
which is gonna make everything else today feel like a piece of cake.
これで、今日の他のことが簡単に感じられるでしょう。
All right, first up, you see the sentence here.
まず、ここにある文を見てください。
His mother is a teacher, but what if she isn't? How do you say that?
彼の母は教師ですが、もしそうでなかったら、どう言いますか？
What's the one tiny magical word we need to add? Think about it.
追加する小さな魔法の言葉は何でしょう？考えてみてください。
Boom, there it is. His mother is not a teacher. It's that simple.
はい、彼の母は教師ではありません。これがシンプルです。
Maybe she's secretly a pop star or an astronaut.
もしかしたら、彼女は秘密のポップスターか宇宙飛行士かもしれません。
The point is, with just that one little word, not,
要は、その小さな言葉「not」で、全体の意味が変わります。
you change the whole story. Okay, you're on a roll.
さて、次に行きましょう。
Let's try another one. You are busy. How would you make that negative?
「あなたは忙しい」と言ったら、どうやって否定形にしますか？
What if you're totally free, just relaxing? How do you say it?
もしあなたが完全に自由で、リラックスしているなら、どう言いますか？
You got it. You are not busy, which is great,
その通りです。「あなたは忙しくない」と言います。
because it means you have time to hang out with me
それは素晴らしいことです。
and figure this out. See, you're already a pro at this.
なぜなら、私と一緒に過ごす時間があるからです。
Okay, last one for our warm-up. You're doing awesome.
見てください、あなたはもうプロです。
Let's look at this. They are students.
では、ウォームアップの最後の問題です。素晴らしいですね。
But what if they're actually, I don't know, spies in disguise?
これを見てください。「彼らは学生です」。
How would we say they're not students? Perfect, they are not students.
でも、もし彼らが実は、スパイの変装をしているなら、どう言いますか？
I bet you're starting to see the pattern here, right?
完璧です。「彼らは学生ではありません」。
So here's the big simple secret. Whenever you have a B verb, you know,
パターンが見えてきましたね？
words like is, am, or are, and you want to make it negative,
ここでの大きな秘密は、B動詞があるとき、
you just pop the word not right after it.
「is」「am」「are」などの言葉を使い、
That's it, that's the whole rule. Now, here's something you hear
否定形にしたいときは、その後に「not」を追加するだけです。
all the time in America, shortcuts. We love them.
これが全てのルールです。さて、アメリカでよく聞くことがあります。
So instead of saying the full she is not,
ショートカットです。私たちはそれが大好きです。
we usually squish it together. You've got two main ways to do it.
「彼女は忙しくない」と言う代わりに、通常は短縮します。
You can say she's not, or you can say she isn't.
「she's not」または「she isn't」と言えます。
Both are totally natural.
どちらも自然です。
The only one that's a little different is I am not.
少し違うのは「I am not」です。
For that, we pretty much always say I'm not. Okay, review is done.
それはほぼ「I'm not」と言います。さて、復習は終わりです。
You've totally got the B plus not thing down.
あなたは「B plus not」を完全に理解しました。
So now let's add a little action, a little twist.
では、少しアクションを加えましょう。
We're gonna start talking about what people are not doing.
人々が何をしていないかについて話し始めます。
Check this out. On the left, you see our old sentence,
これを見てください。左側に古い文があります。
they are not students. And on the right, we've added an action,
「彼らは学生ではありません」。右側にはアクションを追加しました。
they are not studying. Now, look really closely.
「彼らは勉強していません」。さて、よく見てください。
Where is the word not in both of those sentences? Hmm.
その2つの文の「not」はどこにありますか？うーん。
Okay, are you ready for the amazing mind- blowing secret?
さて、驚くべき秘密の準備はできましたか？
The rule is exactly the same. It doesn't change one bit.
ルールは全く同じです。全く変わりません。
You literally already know how to do this. How cool is that?
あなたはこれをすでに知っています。すごいですね。
No new rule to memorize.
新しいルールを覚える必要はありません。
So here it is, the official formula.
では、公式のフォーミュラです。
For the present progressive negative, all you do is take your B verb,
現在進行形の否定では、B動詞を取り、
add not right after it,
その後に「not」を追加し、
and then put your action verb with ing at the end.
最後に動詞にingを付けます。
That is the whole recipe. Okay, theory time is over.
これが全てのレシピです。さて、理論の時間は終わりです。
You know the rule, you've seen how it works,
ルールは知っていますし、どう機能するかも見ました。
now it's time to actually use it.
さあ、実際に使う時間です。
Let's do a little pop quiz to lock this in, ready?
少しポップクイズをやってみましょう。準備はいいですか？
First question, the words are all mixed up.
最初の質問です。言葉がすべて混ざっています。
You've got playing, not, and is.
「playing」「not」「is」があります。
Can you put them back in the right order
これらを正しい順番に並べて、
to say what John isn't doing right now? Go for it.
ジョンが今何をしていないかを言ってみてください。どうぞ。
And the answer is, John is not playing soccer now.
答えは、ジョンは今サッカーをしていません。
Yeah, of course not. He's probably at home, headset on,
そう、もちろんしていません。彼はおそらく家で、
yelling at the screen while playing video games
ヘッドセットをつけて、
with his friends online.
画面に向かって叫びながら
That's a classic American afternoon right there.
オンラインで友達とゲームをしています。
All right, challenge number two. For anyone who speaks Japanese,
これがアメリカの典型的な午後です。
how do we get this idea into English?
さて、次の挑戦です。日本語を話す人に、
We something something doing homework now.
このアイデアを英語にどうやって表現しますか？
What two little words need to go into those blanks? Yes, you got it.
「We something something doing homework now.」
We are not doing homework now.
その空欄に入る2つの言葉は？はい、正解です。
Nope, we are doing something way more fun. We're mastering English.
「We are not doing homework now.」
And here we go, the final boss battle of our pop quiz.
いいえ、私たちはもっと楽しいことをしています。英語をマスターしています。
The words are not, swimming are.
さあ、ポップクイズの最後のボスバトルです。
Put those puzzle pieces together and make a sentence. You can do this.
言葉は「not」「swimming」「are」です。
And the answer is, they are not swimming in the pool now.
そのパズルのピースを組み合わせて文を作ってください。できますよ。
Makes sense, right? I mean, maybe it's the middle of winter
答えは、彼らは今プールで泳いでいません。
or maybe it's a school night. Who goes swimming then?
納得できますよね？冬の真っ最中かもしれませんし、
You crushed that quiz. Well done. Okay, you made it.
学校の夜かもしれません。誰がその時に泳ぎますか？
You did the review, you learned the new rule, you aced the quiz.
クイズを見事にクリアしました。素晴らしいです。さて、終わりました。
So what's the one big idea,
復習をして、新しいルールを学び、クイズに合格しました。
The one thing you absolutely need to remember from all this.
では、ここからの大事なポイントは何でしょうか？
Let's talk about your new grammar superpower. Here it is.
あなたの新しい文法のスーパーパワーについて話しましょう。これです。
The most important thing to remember is that it doesn't matter if you're saying what
最も重要なのは、誰かが何をしているかに関係なく、
someone is or what someone is doing.
否定文を作るルールは常に同じだということです。
The rule for making it negative is always, always the same.
「not」はB動詞のすぐ後に来ます。
Not goes right after the B verb.
これは、私たちが話したすべてに適用されるシンプルなルールです。
It's one simple rule that works for everything we talked about.
これで終わりです。最後にこの質問を残します。
And that's a wrap. So I'll leave you with this one last question.
今、この瞬間、あなたは何をしていないですか？考えてみてください。
Right now, this very second, what are you not doing? Think about it.
あなたは寝ていません。ジェットコースターに乗っていません。
You are not sleeping. You are not riding a roller coaster.
あなたはこの説明を終わらせていて、素晴らしい仕事をしています。ほら？
You are finishing this explainer and you're doing a great job. See?
もう使っていますね。今日は素晴らしい仕事でした。